<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on</title><link>https://cloudprober.org/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudprober.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Cloudprober</title><link>https://cloudprober.org/docs/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudprober.org/docs/about/</guid><description>Posted&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;Sep 05, 2023 by Manu Garg&amp;nbsp;&amp;hyphen;&amp;nbsp;3 min&amp;nbsp;read Origin #
I started working on Cloudprober in 2016. I was leading the Cloud Networking SRE team at Google at that time. As Google Cloud started to grow big time, we started running into observability issues all over. Customers were finding problems before us, resulting in a lot of time being spent in troubleshooting and communicating back and forth1.
Problem was that Google&amp;rsquo;s existing observability tools didn&amp;rsquo;t work for the external Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Cloudwatch (AWS)</title><link>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/cloudwatch/</guid><description>Cloudprober can natively export metrics to AWS Cloudwatch using the cloudwatch surfacer. Adding the cloudwatch surfacer to cloudprover is as simple as adding the following stanza to the config:
surfacer { type: CLOUDWATCH } Authentication #
The cloudwatch surfacer uses the AWS Go SDK, and supports the default credential chain:
Environment variables. Shared credentials file. If your application uses an ECS task definition or RunTask API operation, IAM role for tasks.</description></item><item><title>Stackdriver (Google Cloud)</title><link>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/stackdriver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/stackdriver/</guid><description>Cloudprober can natively export metrics to Google Cloud Monitoring (formerly, Stackdriver) using stackdriver surfacer. Adding stackdriver surfacer to cloudprober is as simple as adding the following stanza to the config:
surfacer { type: STACKDRIVER } This config will work if you&amp;rsquo;re running on GCP and your VM (or GKE pod) has access to Cloud Monitoring (Stackdriver). If running on any other platform, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to specify the GCP project where you want to send the metrics, and you&amp;rsquo;ll have to configure your environment for Google Application Default Credentials.</description></item><item><title>Surfacers</title><link>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudprober.org/docs/surfacers/overview/</guid><description>One of the biggest strengths of cloudprober is that it can export data to multiple monitoring systems, even simultaneously, just based on simple configuration. Cloudprober does that using a built-in mechanism, called surfacers. Each surfacer type implements interface for a specific monitoring system, for example, cloudwatch surfacer publishes data to AWS Cloudwatch. You can configure multiple surfacers at the same time. If you don&amp;rsquo;t specify any surfacer, prometheus and file surfacers are enabled automatically.</description></item></channel></rss>